<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on ThinkBox</title>
    <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on ThinkBox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 20:43:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.thinkbox.dev/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Filtering Domains with Squid Proxy</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0009-domain-filter-with-squid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 20:43:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0009-domain-filter-with-squid/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Squid is a web proxy with caching and forwarding capabilities, however, this post will not be concerned with caching web content. The focus will be on using Squid to control which domains are accessible to a user, either through blacklisting or whitelisting.
This can be useful for blocking undesired domains, such as those associated with malware or advertisements. On the other hand it can be use to limit what a set of computers in a network can connect to which can potently mitigate the impacts of an attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credential Guard on Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0007-cred-guard-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 17:50:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0007-cred-guard-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post will aim to explain Credential Guard and Virtualization Based Security (VBS) which is the technology that makes it possible. There has been many discussions, papers, and talks about this subject. The goal of this post is for me to write out the technical details of this technology in my own words.
There are many interesting and insightful resources available online that can also help you understand how this technology works, resources I have found useful will be linked in the References section at the end of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locking Down a Workstation with AppLocker</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0004-locking-down-workstation-applocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 23:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0004-locking-down-workstation-applocker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction AppLocker is a powerful component of the Windows operating system that allows an administrator to dictate whether a user has permissions to run a file. There are a few different types of files that can be controlled by AppLocker which include executable files (.exe), DLL files (.dll), Windows Installer files (.msi), PowerShell scripts (.ps1), and packaged applications (these include graphical programs such as Settings and the GUI for Defender).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>