<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Information Security on ThinkBox</title>
    <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/information-security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Information Security on ThinkBox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 22:32:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/information-security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Wazuh and Kibana to Monitor Endpoints</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0014-setting-up-wazuh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 22:32:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0014-setting-up-wazuh/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Wazuh is a host intrusion detection system (HIDS) that is capable of performing log analysis, integrity checking, Windows registry monitoring, rootkit detection, and generating alerts based of a set of predefined rules.
The following picture shows the different components that will be needed on this setup, this picture was found on an article related to this subject. The picture is more specific to OSSEC, however, that is alright since Wazuh is based on OSSEC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Windows Endpoints with Winlogbeat</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0013-monitor-windows-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 22:32:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0013-monitor-windows-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post will introduce the steps needed in order to setup a Windows endpoint to forward logs to Logstash. The following diagram shows a layout of how all the components will interact with each other.
On the Endpoint we have logs that we want to ship to Elasticsearch, these logs include various system logs generated by Windows and Sysmon logs. The Sysmon logs are generated by another program installed on the system which will monitor events related to processes being created and registry values being changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring a Single Node ELK Instance</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0012-configure-single-elk-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 22:32:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0012-configure-single-elk-node/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post will aim to guide you in setting up a ELK stack instance, other posts will go into detail about other aspacts such as monitoring logs on Windows. A brief description will be given on all the components that will be used.
If you are interested in reading more about the technical details of how the different components work please consult the References section, I have linked some interesting articles and videos that can be of use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Implementing PKI with OpenSSL</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0011-pki-with-openssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:44:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0011-pki-with-openssl/</guid>
      <description>#image-section { text-align: center; margin: 1.0em; } #image-section .image-caption { font-style: italic; font-size: 0.8em; }  Introduction This post will aim to give an overview of TLS and public key infrastructure (PKI). This first part of this post will give a theoretical overview of how it works. The second part of the post will demonstrate how to setup a CA with OpenSSL and create certificates for web servers and code singing purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>