<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows Internals on ThinkBox</title>
    <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/windows-internals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows Internals on ThinkBox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:44:07 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/windows-internals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Device Guard Polices from a Golden Image</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0010-device-guard-golden-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:44:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0010-device-guard-golden-image/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Device Guard is a system built into Windows 10 that can help mitigate the effects of a breach by controlling which applications are allowed to run, both processess in userland and drivers in the kernel. After Windows 10 1709 Device Guard is now known as Windows Defender Application Control, however, in this post it will be refereed to as Device Guard.
This post will aim to show the steps taken to configure a Device Guard policy based on a golden image, this is a computer that is configured and has all the needed software installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credential Guard on Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0007-cred-guard-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 17:50:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0007-cred-guard-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post will aim to explain Credential Guard and Virtualization Based Security (VBS) which is the technology that makes it possible. There has been many discussions, papers, and talks about this subject. The goal of this post is for me to write out the technical details of this technology in my own words.
There are many interesting and insightful resources available online that can also help you understand how this technology works, resources I have found useful will be linked in the References section at the end of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>