<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Misc Infrastructure on ThinkBox</title>
    <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/misc-infrastructure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Misc Infrastructure on ThinkBox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 17:15:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/misc-infrastructure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Reverse Proxy with Docker</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0003-create-reverse-proxy-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 17:15:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0003-create-reverse-proxy-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This blog post will explain the concept of a reverse proxy, and will demonstrate the steps that need to be taken in order to create a Nginx reverse proxy inside of Docker.
The concept of a reverse proxy is very simple, a client computer will connect to a central point that will pass their connection on to the desired destination. For example, lets take a look at the diagram below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Active Directory Network From Scratch</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0002-setting-up-ad-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 23:48:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0002-setting-up-ad-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This blog post will show step by step how to setup a basic Active Directory network. The network will consist of four computers, two servers and two clients. There will be a Domain Controller, a DHCP server, a central management station, and of course a desktop for the clients. This can all be seen in the diagram below.
The purpose of the central management desktop for the administrator to easily manage multiple servers at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN with LDAP &#43; 2-Factor Authentication and Network Access Polices</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0001-openvpn-ldap-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 17:27:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0001-openvpn-ldap-auth/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This blog post will explain the steps taken to configure OpenVPN to authenticate users using LDAP authentication and 2-Factor authentication. LDAP authentication will be performed against Active Directory, and 2-Factor authentication will be performed with a Time-based One-Time password (TOTP). Furthermore, the network access of users will be restricted to only what the administrator wants them to access.
This post is split up into 5 sections:
 VPN Server Initial Configuration  Base OpenVPN Configuration  Configuring LDAP Authentication  2-Factor Authentication with TOTP  User Based Network Access Polices   The first section will configure the server on which the VPN server will be setup on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>