<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on ThinkBox</title>
    <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on ThinkBox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 22:21:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Transferring and Seizing FSMO Roles</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0008-transferring-and-seizing-fsmo-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 22:21:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0008-transferring-and-seizing-fsmo-roles/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Within a Active Directory environment there are 5 Flexible single master operation (FSMO) roles that are present, they can either all be on a single domain controller or can be distributed between multiple. There are 2 FSMO roles that are forest wide and 3 that are domain wide.
This post will describe the steps taken in order to either transfer a FSMO role to another server, or seize a FSMO role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credential Guard on Windows</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0007-cred-guard-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 17:50:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0007-cred-guard-windows/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This post will aim to explain Credential Guard and Virtualization Based Security (VBS) which is the technology that makes it possible. There has been many discussions, papers, and talks about this subject. The goal of this post is for me to write out the technical details of this technology in my own words.
There are many interesting and insightful resources available online that can also help you understand how this technology works, resources I have found useful will be linked in the References section at the end of the post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating and Rolling Back ESXi</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0006-update-rollback-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:15:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0006-update-rollback-esxi/</guid>
      <description>Updating ESXi For this example I will be updating ESXi build 8169922 to ESXi build 13981272 . You can check the current build of an ESXi box by running the following command:
1 2 3  [root@testesxi:~] vmware -v VMware ESXi 6.7.0 build-8169922 [root@testesxi:~]   Updates come in the form of ZIP files, this ZIP file is usually downloaded from VMWare website .
After an update file is retrieved check that the hash of the file matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving ESXi Configuration State</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0005-esxi-save-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 22:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0005-esxi-save-state/</guid>
      <description>Saving the configuration state of a standalone ESXi server will allow for the restoration of all configurations if a new instance is installed. This will include all virtual machines registrations, switches, port groups, and system configurations.
Backing Up State Running auto-backup.sh will write the current configuration onto the disk, which is stored in /bootbank/state.tgz. ESXi has a cronjob that will run this script every hour, however, if there was a change made recently and you are backing up the configuration it would be best to run this script.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locking Down a Workstation with AppLocker</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0004-locking-down-workstation-applocker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 23:23:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0004-locking-down-workstation-applocker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction AppLocker is a powerful component of the Windows operating system that allows an administrator to dictate whether a user has permissions to run a file. There are a few different types of files that can be controlled by AppLocker which include executable files (.exe), DLL files (.dll), Windows Installer files (.msi), PowerShell scripts (.ps1), and packaged applications (these include graphical programs such as Settings and the GUI for Defender).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Reverse Proxy with Docker</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0003-create-reverse-proxy-with-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 17:15:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0003-create-reverse-proxy-with-docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This blog post will explain the concept of a reverse proxy, and will demonstrate the steps that need to be taken in order to create a Nginx reverse proxy inside of Docker.
The concept of a reverse proxy is very simple, a client computer will connect to a central point that will pass their connection on to the desired destination. For example, lets take a look at the diagram below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Active Directory Network From Scratch</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0002-setting-up-ad-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 23:48:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0002-setting-up-ad-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This blog post will show step by step how to setup a basic Active Directory network. The network will consist of four computers, two servers and two clients. There will be a Domain Controller, a DHCP server, a central management station, and of course a desktop for the clients. This can all be seen in the diagram below.
The purpose of the central management desktop for the administrator to easily manage multiple servers at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenVPN with LDAP &#43; 2-Factor Authentication and Network Access Polices</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0001-openvpn-ldap-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 17:27:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0001-openvpn-ldap-auth/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This blog post will explain the steps taken to configure OpenVPN to authenticate users using LDAP authentication and 2-Factor authentication. LDAP authentication will be performed against Active Directory, and 2-Factor authentication will be performed with a Time-based One-Time password (TOTP). Furthermore, the network access of users will be restricted to only what the administrator wants them to access.
This post is split up into 5 sections:
 VPN Server Initial Configuration  Base OpenVPN Configuration  Configuring LDAP Authentication  2-Factor Authentication with TOTP  User Based Network Access Polices   The first section will configure the server on which the VPN server will be setup on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>