<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vsphere on ThinkBox</title>
    <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/vsphere/</link>
    <description>Recent content in vsphere on ThinkBox</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 21:16:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.thinkbox.dev/categories/vsphere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Packer and Terraform with Ubuntu on vSphere</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0015-iac-vsphere-webserver-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 21:16:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0015-iac-vsphere-webserver-example/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Packer and Terraform are both tools created by the company Hashicorp , both of these tools aim to provide automation capabilities. Packer has the goal of creating machine images for multiple different platforms. For example, we can create AMIs for EC2 instances on AWS or VMDK/VMX files for VMware. The whole goal is to automate the ability to create a consistent image that can be used by a specific platform, whether it be AWS or VMware products such as vSphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating and Rolling Back ESXi</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0006-update-rollback-esxi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:15:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0006-update-rollback-esxi/</guid>
      <description>Updating ESXi For this example I will be updating ESXi build 8169922 to ESXi build 13981272 . You can check the current build of an ESXi box by running the following command:
1 2 3  [root@testesxi:~] vmware -v VMware ESXi 6.7.0 build-8169922 [root@testesxi:~]   Updates come in the form of ZIP files, this ZIP file is usually downloaded from VMWare website .
After an update file is retrieved check that the hash of the file matches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saving ESXi Configuration State</title>
      <link>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0005-esxi-save-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 22:59:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.thinkbox.dev/posts/0005-esxi-save-state/</guid>
      <description>Saving the configuration state of a standalone ESXi server will allow for the restoration of all configurations if a new instance is installed. This will include all virtual machines registrations, switches, port groups, and system configurations.
Backing Up State Running auto-backup.sh will write the current configuration onto the disk, which is stored in /bootbank/state.tgz. ESXi has a cronjob that will run this script every hour, however, if there was a change made recently and you are backing up the configuration it would be best to run this script.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>